Half the world's weather system is about
to break because usually strong winds
flow in this direction, pushing warm
water away from this coast to this one,
keeping things dry over here and pretty
wet over here. But that system is about
to break because of three ingredients.
First, storms over here create sudden
bursts of wind that move in the opposite
direction of normal wind patterns. And
that can slow or even reverse the
direction of air flow, which causes
change in temperature. Those new wind
patterns push warm water back this way,
which leads to pressure. Because now
it's way warmer over here and way colder
over here than normal. And colder air is
more dense, so the wind wants to flow
this way all of a sudden, flipping the
whole weather system, creating stormy
weather over here and droughts and fire
over here. It's called El Niño. It
happens every 2 to 7 years, and it takes
about a year for things to reset. But
why are there so many more tornadoes in
the US than anywhere else on Earth? If
you want to know the answer, subscribe.